Philip Singer Papers
Philip Singer Papers
- Writings (Box 20)
  - Film review, Lempad of Bali, Choice, Jun 1987 (Box 20)
  - First Spiritualist Church, 1975; includes photographs (Box 20)
  - "The Five Million Holy Men of India," The Reporter, Mar 1952 (Box 20)
  - "Francisco Franko, Spain", 1949 (Box 24)
  - "From Anthropology and Medicine to Therapy and Neo-Colonialism", 1992 (Box 20)
  - #6 Good Visuals, NES, Parent/Child Disch, Messina Phone Patience, 'Wiring' Baby, singer_p_0231; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 43)
  - #7 Good Visuals, Parents, Chapel, Incubator, Baby on Table, Parents Inside, singer_p_0232; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 43)
  - "Grant's Miracles: A Follow Up," Free Inquiry, 1986 (Box 20)
  - "Group Ethnotherapy with Hindu Students in an American University," Indian Journal of Psychoanalysis, 1967-1968; also includes the essay publication in India Horizon (Box 20)
  - "Guyana - Land of Oppression" The Jerusalem Post, Jan 1979 (Box 24)
  - "Health, Welfare, and Development in Latin America and the Caribbean", 1980 (Box 21)
  - "Hinduization and Creolization in Guyana," Social and Economic Studies v. 16 n. 3, 1967; with Enrique Araneta (Box 21)
  - "Human Actualization in a Religious Milieu Spiritual and Clinical Powers of Healing, Case Study of Hindus in Guyana", undated; draft (Box 21)
  - "Hundreds debate future of non-traditional therapies," Brain Mind v. 20 n. 7, 1995 (Box 21)
  - "Hungry for a Miracle," Phoenix: Journal of Transpersonal Anthropology v. 7 nos. 1 and 2, 1983 (Box 21)
  - "Informant Fraud: Lying or Cultural Adaptation", undated (Box 21)
  - "Institution-Building: Some Lessons from Asia", undated; with Ernest Becker (Box 21)
  - "Integration of Indigenous Healing Practices of the Kali Cult with Western Psychiatric Modalities in British Guiana", 1967; with Louis Aarons (Box 21)
  - "Introduction: From Anthropology and Medicine to Therapy and Neo-Colonialism", undated (Box 21)
  - "Is Voodoo Practicing Medicine Without a License", 1982 (Box 21)
  - Jerusalem Post submissions, 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - "Learning of Psychodynamics, History, Diagnosis Management Therapy, By a Kali Cult Indigenous Healer in Guyana", 1973; with Enrique Araneta and Jamsie Naidoo (Box 21)
  - "Livable Culture or Bubble Transcendentalism", 1965; a draft of a speech that was presented at the American Psychological Association meeting (Box 21)
  - "Marketing New High Protein Foods Among Poor People, or Who Should Manipulate the Culture?" Worldmark Press Documentation, 1969 (Box 21)
  - "A Medical Anthropologist's View of American Shamans," Free Inquiry, 1986 (Box 21)
  - "Mukti-Siddhi: An Alternative Integrating Pattern to Explain India as a Total Civilization", 1972 (Box 21)
  - "Nehru's Successors," Samaj Vijnana v. 1 n.1, 1969 (Box 21)
  - "New Myths about the Poor - Ideology Masquerading as Sociology," Indian Sociological Bulletin, Oct 1968 (Box 21)
  - "Nigerian Bush-Doctors and WHO Medicine Men, An Arranged Marriage Without Issue," introduction, An Essay in West Therapeutics, Obadiah Johnson, 1982 (Box 21)
  - "Norway's Solution," New Republican, 1948; with Gilbert Cranberg (Box 21)
  - "The Paradox of O. John Rogge", undated (Box 21)
  - "Philippine Psychic Surgery: From Village Shamanism to Global Alternative Healing", 1985; with Kate W. Ankenbrandt (Box 21)
  - "Philippine Psychic Surgery: From Village Shamanism to Global Alternative Healing", 1973-1985; draft and research (Box 21)
  - "The Private Family, The Affect Counselor and Her Public Family", undated; with Carl R. Vann and Daniel E. Desole (Box 21)
  - "A Project that Failed," Mental Health and Urban Social Policy, 1968; with Daniel E. Desole and Edward Swietnicki (Box 21)
  - "Psychic Surgery: Close Observations of a Popular Healing Practice," Medical Anthropology Quarterly, 1990 (Box 21)
  - "The Relationship Between the Concept of Therapy and the Concept of Responsibility in the Rehabilitation of the Psychiatric Patient", 1971; with Ellis Perlman (Box 21)
  - Reviews, reviews written by Singer
    - "Anthropological Filmmaking: Anthropological Perspectives on the Production of Film and Video for General Public Audiences," Editor Jack R. Rollwagen, Choice, 1989 (Box 21)
    - "Asian Medical Systems," Editor Charles Leslie, American Ethnologist, 1979 (Box 21)
    - "Commentary: Beyond a 'Contribution to Knowledge'? Santeria as Therapy Among Haitian Refugees," Anthropology Newsletter, 1996 (Box 21)
    - "Cultural Change, Mental Health, and Poverty," Joseph C. Finney, American Anthropologist, Apr 1971 (Box 21)
    - "Innovation in Ethnographic Film: From Innocence to Self-Consciousness," Choice, 1955 (Box 21)
    - "New Worlds from Fragments: Film, Ethnography, and the Representation of Northwest Coast Cultures," Choice, Feb 1995 (Box 21)
    - "Psychic Sleuths: ESP and Sensational Cases," Editor Joe Nickell, American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1994 (Box 21)
    - "The Social Welfare Forum," American Anthropologist, Jun 1974 (Box 21)
  - "The Rise and Fall of Medical Education from Flexner's Surgery to Curriculum Gimmickry", undated (Box 21)
  - "Ritual and Art in India and Japan: Some Implications for Anthropology", 1973 (Box 21)
  - "Scientific and Medical Advances in Rehabilitation Medicine", circa 1966 (Box 22)
  - "Signs of the Times, or, Reconciliation and Secularization", 1972; an address given to Siena Heights College (Box 22)
  - "Society and the Exceptional Child", 1965 (Box 22)
  - "A Study in Ethnopsychiatry, Religions Healing in British Healing in British Guiana: Kali and Obeah", 1963 (Box 22)
  - "Suicide and Role Strain Among Physicians," The International Journal of Social Psychiatry v. 15 n. 4, 1969 (Box 22)
  - "A Theory of Mental Illness", circa 1965 (Box 22)
  - "Thesis: Cultural Anthropology and Community Psychiatry; Antithesis: World Health Organization and Basic Health Services; Synthesis: Community Development", 1975; with Enrique Araneta (Box 22)
  - "The Tonnara-Mattanza and Cultural Identity in Favignana," International Journal of Island Affairs, Nov 1999 (Box 22)
  - "Tourette's Syndrome Symptom Onset at Age Thirty-five," The International Journal of Social Psychiatry, 1979; with Enrique Araneta, Jed Magen, Michael N. Musci Jr., and Carl R. Vann (Box 22)
  - "Toward a Comparison of Suicide Rates in Scandinavian and Four Eastern European Countries", 1970; with Sallie Krauss, Carl R. Vann, and Daniel E. DeSole (Box 22)
  - "Towards a Reevaluation of the Concept of Charisma with Reference to India," The Michigan Academician, 1971 (Box 22)
  - "Traditional African Medicine and Eradication of Smallpox," The New England Journal of Medicine, Apr 1981; commentary with Carl Vann (Box 22)
  - "Traditional Healing: A Dilemma for Medicine and Religion," Advances in Medical Social Science v. 2, 1984 (Box 22)
  - "Traditional Healing and the Medical/Psychiatric Mafia", 1977 (Box 22)
  - "Two Gods That Are Failing for Medical Anthropologists: Chinese Traditional Medicine and the World Health Organization Traditional Medicine Program, 1985 (Box 22)
  - "The University as a Therapeutic Community," Change v. 4 n. 5, Jun 1972; with Carl R. Vann (Box 22)
  - "The Use of Traditional Healers and Para-Professionals in Developed Countries - the USA Implications for Policy and Research in Developing Countries", 1976; draft (Box 22)
  - "USSR in Mid-East", undated (Box 22)
  - "A Visit to Franco's Spain", 1949; with Gilbert Cranberg (Box 22)
- Miscellaneous media
  - Adrian Commencement Speech; Seena Heights / Adrian Dominican Talks, 1972; singer_p_0838; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
  - The African Diaspora in DFR, singer_p_1448; DVD; running time 25:00 (Box 55)
  - Aging / Mortality Anthros, singer_p_1566; Flash Memory: USB (Box 43)
  - Alicudi, Italy, Lo Monaco, singer_p_1371; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 54)
  - Alicudi, Italy, Lo Monaco, singer_p_1372; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 54)
  - Allport Lecture, 1972/10/24; singer_p_0800; there is crossed out text on tape; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 49)
  - Antonio Vivaldi: Five Concerti, singer_p_0842; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 50)
    A full description provided on the tape reads: "Angelicum Orchestra: Emilio Suvini, Conductor. Concerto in G major for Strings and Harpsichord "Alla Rustica"; Concerto in C major for 2 flutes, 2 oboes, bassoon, 2 violins, strings and harpsichord; Concerto in d minor for 2 flutes, 2 oboes, bassoon, 2 violins, strings and harpsichord."
  - Aragones, Pak, Ullman, Keischl, Bob and M. Pease Meeting, 1982/02/05; singer_p_0779; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Aranetta and Philip Singer Discusses Juan Blanche, singer_p_0769; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Argentina, Hermanas, 10/03/2005; singer_p_0437; label on tape reads, "Interview with Julian, NYC, 305 W. 28 ST. 5:30 PM"; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Argentina Hermanas, 2005/10/03; singer_p_1243; interview with Julia from NYC; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 6)
  - "Assignment Alaska", singer_p_0117; label reads, "Copy of Assignment Alaska"; VHS; running time 60:00 (Box 34)
  - At Whose Expense? Cancell for Cancer, singer_p_1458; DVD; running time 75:00 (Box 55)
  - Auggier, kid, 1997; singer_p_0314; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
  - Ayurvedic Medicine, Dr. Vasant Lad, Summit U. Eliz. Prophet, singer_p_1394; DVD; running time 58:00 (Box 55)
  - [B.F.] Skinner, [Leon] Festinger, [William] Buckley, 1973/11/03; singer_p_0559; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Bach (Herbal) Remedies, Dr. Jungreis, singer_p_0624; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Bagel-maker/Hadera, 03/27/1979; singer_p_0508; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Bali, singer_p_0228; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 42)
  - Barbara Turner, 05/10/1984; singer_p_0499; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Bascal Naridoo, singer_p_0223; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 42)
  - Basic Relaxation Exercise/Mindfulness Meditation, singer_p_0542; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - The Battle of Algiers, singer_p_1362; DVD; running time 120:00 (Box 53)
  - Bear Lodge, New Town, N.D., 1985/07/20; singer_p_0629; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Beating Fire, 09/27/2009; singer_p_0410; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Bernard and His Village (English version), singer_p_0124; VHS (Box 34)
  - Bharati, Ragas, singer_p_0643; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - The Bible Buried in Secrets, singer_p_1447; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
  - Birth of DooWop, 1948-1959, singer_p_0715; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Black Seminoles: A Celebration of Survival, 1981; singer_p_0717; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Blessing Prayer, Baptist Church of the Good Shepherd, singer_p_0729; with Pastor David Epley; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Bone Marrow Transplant #1, singer_p_1550; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 43)
  - Botanica, 05/24/2004; singer_p_0408; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Bronowski, singer_p_0789; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Bryce Bond, Metro Airport, Example of "Normal" "Crazy" Astral Plate Talk, 1980; singer_p_0642; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 2)
  - "Calling Out Patients," Life Story, 4 Ways God Speaks, 1982/07/11; singer_p_0796; W.V. Grant; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
  - Can You Say Circus?, 2000; singer_p_1412; DVD; running time 85:00 (Box 55)
  - Carla Sango Ritual at Home, 1995/12/02; singer_p_1508; Hi8; running time 94:00 (Box 58)
  - Carla HUA, 1995/08/19; singer_p_1510; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 58)
  - Carla, Margegnito, Pierre; Lansing, singer_p_1507; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 58)
  - "Caste", singer_p_0560; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - A Certain Sacrifice, singer_p_1189; dubbed in Italian; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Ch L Library, Physical Difference, Metaphysical (3 parts), singer_p_0635; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Children Psychology, Hyperactive Child, Evaluation, and Management; Childhood Rape; Group Therapy, 1973; singer_p_0686; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 2)
  - China Medicinal Herb Factory (No Translation, Government Film), singer_p_1086; DVD; running time 11:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Chinese Cuisine and The American Palate, singer_p_0022; VHS; running time 46:37 (Box 26)
  - Chip wedding dance, singer_p_0391; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Chris Bury, Osteopath, 5 Patients Interview, singer_p_1505; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 58)
  - CKLW Morning Show, 1978/04/06; singer_p_0530; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Clenter Valley Health, Talk to Open Retreat, 1982; singer_p_0860; title is handwritten and the first word is mostly illegible, and may not reflect the actual title; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 50)
  - Clozapine Drug, 1991/03/20; singer_p_0554; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Coco Cola (Old/New) on Sperm, singer_p_0657; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Comments on Psychic Surgery, Sheely, Singer, Uphoff, Commitment at Johns Hopkins, 1982/08/08; singer_p_0621; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Complementary Health in England: Acupuncture for Pain Relief, singer_p_1434; DVD; running time 56:00 (Box 55)
  - Complimentary Health Therapists in England: Touching, Reflexology, Massage, singer_p_1375; DVD; running time 87:00 (Box 54)
  - Corn Bank, Public Health PX, singer_p_0129; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 35)
  - CPC China Trip, December 29, 1998 - January 6, 1999, Shanghai, Xian, Beijing, singer_p_0225; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 42)
  - CPC China Trip, December 29, 1998 - January 6, 1999, Shanghai, Xian, Beijing, singer_p_0226; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 42)
  - Crash, singer_p_1359; 2004 movie about racial and social tensions in Los Angeles; DVD; running time 115:00 (Box 53)
  - Creation, singer_p_1415; DVD; running time 30:00 (Box 55)
  - Creation vs. Evolution, 1982/07/11; singer_p_0795; Ann Arbor debate; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
  - Curanderas, Texas, singer_p_1395; DVD; running time 15:00 (Box 55)
  - Curanderos South Texas, S.W. Center for Educational T.V., singer_p_1102; DVD; running time 15:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Decoding the Pass, Bible Origin, singer_p_1335; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 53)
  - Deep: Siddha Bda, singer_p_0823; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Box 49)
  - Demo and talks at MH, singer_p_0217; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 42)
  - A Detroit Black Church and a Cherokee Woman Shaman, 1994; singer_p_1285; DVD; running time 59:00 (Oversize 6)
    Text on case reads: Wanita interviews a pastor she ordained, W. talks about white 'race' culture, blacks most open. Wanita cut aways, discuss crystals. Wanita reads cards for church devotees, prices for 'seal' anger oil, medicine bag."
  - Diversity, Rap on Race, Mead/Baldwin, singer_p_0622; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 2)
  - "Doda" Oleah talk: CCN, Mother Brown, Black-Brown Racial Discussion, 1975/08/02; singer_p_0857; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
  - Dr. Fujiki, 1984/06/28; singer_p_0517; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Dr. Fujiki (2 of 2), 1984/06/28; singer_p_0513; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Dr. Kanti Girl - Nepal - WHO, Dr. Srivastiav Ind. Govt. Director Medical Services, 12/30/1975; singer_p_0525; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Dr. Motoyama F.H.H.F. (Tape #1), 10/31/1981; singer_p_0489; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Drugs President Speech, 01/28/1998; singer_p_0484; VHS: VHS-C; running time 30:00 (Box 48)
  - Drums of Passion; Interview with King/Yoruba Village, singer_p_0639; label on case reads, "Gardner testimony"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Dylan at Budokan (DeSole), singer_p_0551; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - E=MC2, Einstein NOVA, singer_p_1407; DVD; running time 75:00 (Box 55)
  - Ecuador Evil Wind - Evil Air, "Pasma," Protein Calorie Malnutrition, singer_p_1107; English subtitles; DVD; running time 22:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Ed Newman Interview C. Levi Strauss, 1973/02/26; singer_p_0668; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Eduardo The Healer 1978, Peruvian folk doctor, singer_p_0132; label on case reads, "transfer from 3/4"; VHS; running time 55:00 (Box 35)
  - Emeliese #1, singer_p_0414; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Eric Smith, Frontline, singer_p_0122; label on box reads, "Ch. 7 and Frontline, Eric Smith"; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 34)
  - Eskimo Dance, 1991/02/07; singer_p_1283; text on disc reads, "Eskimo youth dances, drumming/singing, school kitchen, community dining, guests from Soviet Union, adult sing/drum/dance, king is dancers at rec center"; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Espiritistas Singing in Flores Chapel, 1985/11/18; singer_p_0742; Dr. Alfred Stelter and Jamie Licauco; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
  - The Everyday Heroics of Living, singer_p_0504; produced by Psychology Today; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Exmouth AIDS CTR, Reflexology, Massage, 1992/04/08; singer_p_1504; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 57)
  - Fantasy, Image and the Ethic of Science, DG Haring, singer_p_1419; CD; running time 70:00 (Box 55)
  - Fantasy, Image, and the Ethic of Science, 04/20/1961; singer_p_0501; label on tape, "08 October 1974 - copy date"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Father Cares: Jonestown, 1981/04/23; singer_p_0564; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Flint Class, Tarot Shaman, 1988; singer_p_0851; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 50)
  - Folk Healing, 1979/09/18; singer_p_0566; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Follow the Leader, singer_p_1181; DVD; running time 24:00 (Oversize 5)
  - 4/SX Part II incomplete, singer_p_1431; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
  - Frontier, 1960/11/07; singer_p_1530; label on case reads, "tape to reuse, Does A Frontier Folklore Experience Make A Constructive Contribution to [Illegible]? Interview with 4 students; H. Cleveland [Illegible] News Coverage"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 43)
  - Gardner (Tape 2), singer_p_0531; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Giant Blue Fin Tuna, All Things Considered, 1996/11/29; singer_p_0543; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Gifts of the Spirit: Pastor David Epley, 1987/06/20; singer_p_0534; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Gioacchino Cataldo / Vincenzo Zabarino, 1997; singer_p_0812; Gioacchino Cataldo was an Italian fisherman; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 49)
  - Il Giorni Della Shoah, singer_p_1227; DVD; running time 41:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Godot [illegible], singer_p_0807; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
  - Goethe-Institut, singer_p_0820; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 49)
  - The Great American/International Brass Band Festival, singer_p_1231; festival in Danville, Kentucky; DVD; running time 21:50 (Oversize 6)
  - Great Faith Ministry, Healing Water, 1996/01/26; singer_p_1528; Hi8; running time 90:00 (Box 58)
  - Grupo de Terapia Artistico, Frida Kahlo, singer_p_1426; DVD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
  - Hail Mother Kali, 1988; singer_p_1405; handwritten text on case reads, "Jamsie pics - drums/sings/talks, by S. Stephanides, compare to P[hilip] S[inger] / 3-Day Puja"; DVD; running time 58:00 (Box 55)
  - Haiti, Ogun, singer_p_1248; scripted choreography and documentary; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 6)
  - The Haitians, The Healers, The Anthropologist: 2 Case Studies, singer_p_1234; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Hands on Health Care: The Profession of Physical Therapy, 1994; singer_p_1286; DVD; running time 12:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Hare Krishina Debate Press Interview Bharati, Hridaynanda, 1973; singer_p_0805; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 49)
  - Healing Water: Great Faith Ministry, January 26, 1996; singer_p_0141; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 36)
  - Healing: Lou Gordon Interview with William Nolen, MD; Pokhara Holy Man, Nepal, 1976/10/24; singer_p_0827; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
  - Health Behavior Sciences, Professor P. Singer Oakland University: "Rap" on Health, singer_p_1171; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 5)
  - Health for All Kenya - WHO, singer_p_0138; VHS (Box 36)
  - Health Through God's Pharmacy, singer_p_0140; Label on tape reads, "Summit Uni. - Pro LS, Maria Treben"; VHS; running time 58:00 (Box 36)
  - The Heart of Healing: Remarkable Stories of How We Heal Ourselves, Part 1-3, singer_p_0142; label on box reads, "Part 1: What we believe, Part 2: How we change, Part 3: Who we become"; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 36)
  - The Heart of the Matter #2, singer_p_1382; CD; running time 120:00 (Box 54)
  - Hesperian Foundation Health Care by the People, singer_p_1432; the; DVD; running time 26:00 (Box 55)
  - Hiroshima, 1975/12/15; singer_p_0579; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 1)
  - The Holmes Center Symposium, "The Search for Healing: A Decade of Progress"; Marcel Vogel, "Crystals, Healing and Medicine", 1983; singer_p_0714; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Holy Man at Mob, singer_p_0587; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Holy Man at Mob (Tape 1 of 2), singer_p_0588; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Homeless, singer_p_0400; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Homeopathy, Summit University, singer_p_1251; DVD; running time 47:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Hospital Wiseman (Part 1), singer_p_1391; DVD; running time 55:00 (Box 55)
  - Hospitals #2, singer_p_1445; DVD; running time 25:00 (Box 55)
  - Imagery and Body Sense, 1985/08/23; singer_p_0648; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Ind. Ed. CTR James Lee, Med. Bear Academy, 1995/05/12; singer_p_1503; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 57)
  - "Indian/Hindu Religious Doctrine", singer_p_0509; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Interview with Sensei by Chris Alsten, 1982/07/23; singer_p_0563; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Israeli, 1979/03/05; singer_p_0593; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 2)
  - "Italian film", singer_p_0145; VHS; running time 160:00 (Box 36)
  - Italy Village Games, singer_p_0143; label on tape reads, "Greased pole, tug of war, potato bag race"; VHS; running time 180:00 (Box 36)
  - Iwabuchi, Mrs., Shrine Secretary, Interview (#1 of 2), 1984/06/12; singer_p_0568; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
  - JN [Jamsie Naidoo] Royal Oak PTA, Marygrove Catholic College, 1973/12/09; singer_p_0804; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Box 49)
  - Jacob Lawrence Art, singer_p_0222; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 42)
  - Josh Groban Collection, singer_p_1457; various songs by Josh Groban; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
  - K. Mai Teaser, singer_p_1565; Flash Memory: USB (Box 43)
  - Kali "Lewis" Jamaica, NY, 04/12/2009; singer_p_0403; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Kali Film Fest, 04/26/2009; singer_p_0402; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Kalo #12: Mental Ill Santeria, 2006/04/03; singer_p_1363; DVD; running time 120:00 (Box 53)
  - Karlovy Vary Spa; Interview with Dr. Hebron; Spa Facilities Therapy, singer_p_1526; Hi8; running time 58:00 (Box 58)
  - Karlsruhe Conference, 1981/04/25; singer_p_0828; additional handwritten text on tape is illegible; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 49)
  - Karlsruhe: Dr. Leitz, Seutemon, 1981/04/25; singer_p_0831; additional handwritten text on tape is illegible; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 50)
  - Kate A. Interviews Elizabeth Scriba, 1985/09/22; singer_p_0672; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)